Now that you've written your sentence down, try shifting the stress around in
your own language by going through the stress patterns. Don't try to put on a
particular American or other accent. Just concentrate on stressing a different word
in the sentence each time you say it. For example, if your language is German, ich
habe nicht gesagt, dass er das Geld gestohlen hat, you would change the stress
to, ich habe nicht gesagt, dass er das Geld gestohlen
If you translated it into French, you would say,
Or,
In Japanese, many people think there are no intonation changes, but if you hear
someone say, you'll realize that it has similarities to every other language.
Or,
No matter how strange it may sound to you, stress each different word several times
in your language. You may notice that with some words it sounds perfectly normal, but
with other words it sounds very strange. Or you may find that in your language,
rather than stressing a word, you prefer to change the word order or substitute
another word. Whatever you do is fine, as long as you realize where your language
patterns are similar to and different from the American English intonation patterns.
Then, when you do it again in English, it'll be much easier. Note, an excellent
exercise is to practice speaking your native language with an American accent.
If you can sound like an American speaking your native language, imagine how easy it
would be to speak English with an American accent. Practice shifting the stressed
words in your native language.